

# **MARHIC JEROME**

Back End Developer (Ruby on Rails)

**.** +33 7 68 18 51 36

France

in	linkedin.com/in/	jerome-marhic-53642216
	mincum.com, m,	jeronie manne eee+22 re

jeromemarhic.com

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Experienced web developer (Computer Science MSc - 3 years Ruby On Rails, 2 years C++ development) looking for a lead or senior engineer role in backend web development.

In my previous positions I learned the value of writing simple and readable modules along with tests and code reviews, when maintaining existing projects or developing new ones.

My current stack is Ruby on Rails and Postgres for the back end, React on the frontend and Docker/Kubernetes/CircleCI on the Ops end. I am fluent in English and advanced in Japanese.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Back End Engineer (Freelance)

2017 - 2019 (remote)

Supporting the Effilab business needs by integrating various APIs (Facebook, Aircall, Mailchimp, Meero, etc.) with our Rails 5.2 app, maintaining our Graphql API and implementing Sidekiq jobs for reporting.

Unit & Integration Tests (Rspec, Capybara), CI/CD (CircleCI, deployment with Kubernetes on Google Cloud Platform)

Multiple side apps (React SPA/Google Addon etc)

## **Technologies used:**

Ruby on Rails Sidekiq Docker Rspec/Capybara Pos

Postgres (Kubernetes/Helm) (Stackdriver)

## O Web Developer Prium Solutions

2016 - 2017 (Paris)

Junior web developer at Prium solutions (design and development consultancy)

Worked on existing and new projects, support, deployment etc.

#### **Technologies used:**

Ruby on Rails Linux Nginx Git

# Software Engineer

2011 - 2013 (Seoul)

Video game developer for MLB 2K series. UI/UX, AI.

#### **Technologies used:**

(C++)

**OpenGL** 

<u>Effilab</u>

Visual Concepts Korea

## **SKILLS & TOOLS**

#### **Backend**

Ruby on Rails

SQL

Kubernetes (Helm)

#### **Others**

Graphql DevOps Git Unit Testing Python Machine Learning

## **EDUCATION**

Cloud (AWS/GCP)

## **MSc in Computer Science**

INSA Rennes, France 2006 - 2011

#### **Exchange program**

Rochester Institute of Technology, USA 2011-2012

## **LANGUAGES**

French (Native)

English (Fluent - TOEIC 985)

Japanese (Advanced - JLPT N1)

# **OTHERS**

